KATHRYN M. ADDABBO

908-655-6722 ★ <u>kaddabbo@gmail.com</u> ★ <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kathrynaddabbo</u>
For more detail, visit my personal website: <u>https://kaddabbo.github.io/</u>

Biostatistician experienced in working in a risk analytics capacity with prior exposure to pharmaceuticals and neurobiology research. Skilled troubleshooter, accomplished in data cleaning/aggregating, statistical modeling and machine learning.

- ♦ Competencies: R, Shiny, SQL, Tableau, Alteryx & MS Office
- ♦ Applied Skills: Advanced critical thinking and problem-solving
- ♦ **Gifted Technical Communicator:** Outstanding verbal and written communication abilities with proven expertise presenting data to stakeholders

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Biostatistics | Columbia University, Mailman School of Public Health

Coursework in Biostatistical Methods, Data Science, Probability, Statistical Inference, Longitudinal Data Analysis, Epidemiology & Randomized Clinical Trials

Bachelor of Science, Biochemistry | University at Buffalo, The State University of New York (SUNY)

Coursework in Biochemistry, Physical, Organic & Inorganic Chemistry, Calculus, Linear Algebra & Differential Equations

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HEALTHFIRST: New York, NY

June 2018 – August 2018

Clinical Informatics & Analytics Intern | Insurance

Evaluated the effect of distance from a member's home to their primary care provider's office on their number of preventable admission (PQIs) over a period of two years. Worked on a team to complete descriptive analysis of the opioid abusers in the member population.

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY: New York, NY

November 2017 – December 2018

Student Projects

Various group projects were completed while enrolled in the master's program:

- Unsupervised learning to predict the effect of specific amino acid mutations (benign or pathogenic) using various pathogenicity likelihood, 3D clustering and evolutionary conservation scores
- Longitudinal analysis of health outcomes effected by smoking with data from the Framingham Heart Study
- Supervised learning methods investigated what covariates influenced price; unsupervised machine learning methods attempted to predict borough location with data from Airbnb in New York City
- Exploratory analysis of tweets in the United States over a 48-hour time period, incorporating sentiment analysis

HUNTER JAMES KELLY RESEARCH INSTITUTE: Buffalo, NY

January 2015 - May 2016

Research Assistant | Laboratory of Dr. Laura Feltri

Investigated the absence of specific alpha or beta integrin subunits and their effect on the early stages of myelination. Collaborated on a research team and worked independently to perform tests, analyze results and report findings.

- ♦ Completed DNA extraction and polymerase chain reaction
- Skilled in cell culture techniques (Schwann cells and DRG co-culture specifically) and immunohistochemistry
- Performed mouse sciatic nerve, rat embryo spinal cord and DRG dissections

CELGENE CORPORATION: Basking Ridge & Berkeley Heights, NJ

Full Time, Summers & Winters 2013 – 2016

Pharmaceutical Intern | Global Regulatory Chemical Manufacturing & Controls

Assisted with the preparation of documents and protocols necessary for drug trial submission. Updated standard operating procedures and manufacturer impurities information to fit regulatory and compliance needs.

- Drafted change notices and quality overall summaries
- ♦ Produced stability tables to submit to FDA
- ♦ Modified and integrated new acquisition drug trial documents with Celgene's regulatory guidelines